Guide to the Frances D. Acomb Papers, 1953 - 1975
University Archives Duke University
Frances D. Acomb papers 1953 - 1975
Acomb, Frances Dorothy, 1907-
0.5 Linear Feet 500 Items
University Archives, Duke University
Frances D. Acomb (1907-1984) served as a professor of history at Duke University from 1945 to 1975. She specialized in French history. The Acomb papers contain correspondence, memoranda, manuscripts, and printed matter dealing with Acomb's study of European history, particularly Jacques Mallet Du Pan; as well as the Duke University chapter of the American Association of University Professors, the American Association of University Women, and other professional organizations.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Frances D. Acomb Papers was received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1990.
Biographical Note
Frances Dorothy Acomb was born in Donora, Pa. in 1907. She earned a B.A. from Wellesley College (1928), an M.A. from Smith College (1932), and a Ph.D. from the University of Chicago (1943). After teaching history in high schools and colleges from 1929-1944, Acomb worked as a historian in the War Department from 1944 to 1945. She served as a Professor of History at Duke University in 1945 until her retirement in 1975. She published the book, Mallet du Pan (1749-1800); a career in political journalism, in 1973. In addition, Acomb participated in a number of professional organizations, including the American Association of University Professors, the American Association of University Women, the American Historical Association, and the Society for French Historical Studies. Frances Acomb died on January 19, 1984.
Collection Overview
The papers contain correspondence, memoranda, manuscripts, and printed matter dealing with Acomb's study of modern European history, particularly Jacques Mallet Du Pan. Acomb's memberships in the Duke University chapter of the American Association of University Professors and the American Association of University Women are documented through minutes and other materials.
Arrangement
Items are arranged alphabetically.
Subject Headings
These and related materials may be accessed under the following subject headings in the Duke University Libraries online catalog.
Acomb, Frances Dorothy, 1907-
Mallet du Pan, M. (Jacques), 1749-1800.
American Association of University Professors.
American Association of University Women.
Duke University -- Faculty.
Duke University. Dept. of History.
Contents of Collection
- 1990 Accession [A90-76]
  - AAUP -- Duke Chapter, 1954-1958
  - AAUW, 1958-1968
  - Commentary on K. Brace's Paper -- AHA 1951
  - Consortium on Revolutionary Europe -- 5th Annual Meeting, 1974-1975
  - Correspondence with Students, 1961-1974; C. V.; History Dept. Newsletters, 1953-1972
  - Graduate Students -- Correspondence, 1964-1965
  - Library -- General Information, 1973
  - M.A. Thesis -- John White, 1961-1962
  - Paper on Mallet Du Pan--Read at SHA, Nov. 1953
  - Professional Historical Organizations, 1949-1972
  - Publications -- The International Peacetime Conference, 1904-1914, 1933
  - Sabbatical Leaves, 1958-1972
Related Material
American Association of University Professors Records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Dept. of History Records.
University Archives, Duke University.